Finding aid for the Nathan Pritikin papers LSC.1628
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Speaking Engagements
  - Schedules, 1980
    - "Today" Show, September 18, 1981. (Box 16)
    - Management Accounting Practise Conference. Kansas City, September 22, 1981. (Box 16)
    - American Association of Fitness Directors. Florida, September 24, 1981. (Box 16)
    - Pratt & Whitney Fitness Program. Florida, September 25, 1981. (Box 16)
    - Robinson's. Santa Monica, October 1, 1981. (Box 16)
    - University of California. San Diego, October 3-4, 1981. (Box 16)
    - American Dental Association. Kansas City, October 27, 1981. (Box 16)
    - Deborah Heart & Lung Center Forum. New Jersey, October 29, 1981. (Box 16)
    - Peninsula Hospital Center. New York, October 30, 1981. (Box 16)
    - New York University Dental Center, October 31, 1981. (Box 16)
    - LSU Dental School. New Orleans, November 6, 1981. (Box 16)
    - Milwaukee: PR Appearances - Bantam Books, November 9, 1981. (Box 16)
    - Santa Barbara City College, November 13, 1981. (Box 16)
    - National Charity League. Glendale, November 19, 1981. (Box 16)
    - Long Beach Medical Association, November 19, 1981. (Box 16)
    - Swedish Covenant Hospital. Chicago, December 7, 1981. (Box 16)
  - 1982
    - The Houstonian Foundation, January 22, 1982. (Box 16)
    - American Medical Joggers Association, January 23, 1982. (Box 16)
    - Los Angeles County Medical Association, March 11, 1982. (Box 16)
    - Academy of General Dentistry. Chicago, March 14, 1982. (Box 16)
    - Roseville Community Hospital, March 18, 1982. (Box 16)
    - Sacramento District Dental Society, March 19, 1982. (Box 16)
    - Bantam Books: PR Tour, March 15-April 9, 1982. (Box 16)
    - Greater Long Island Dental Meeting. New York, April 1, 1982. (Box 16)
    - New York Hospital, Cornell Medical Center, April 30, 1982. (Box 16)
    - Kirksville College of Osteopathic Medicine, June 6, 1982. (Box 16)
    - Young Presidents Organization, June 8, 1982. (Box 16)
    - Cedars-Sinai Hospital, June 21, 1982. (Box 16)
    - Dalton Books, July 8, 1982. (Box 16)
    - Real Foods, Incorporated. Allentown, Pennsylvania, July 10, 1982. (Box 16)
    - Parker Chiropractic. San Francisco, July 17, 1982. (Box 16)
    - Family Practise Symposium. Tarzana, September 7, 1982. (Box 16)
    - Placentia Linda Community Hospital, September 27, 1982. (Box 16)
    - American Academy of Periodontology. Anaheim, October 6, 1982. (Box 16)
    - International Heart Foundation. Phoenix, October 10, 1982. (Box 16)
    - Australia Tour, October 1982. (Box 16)
    - Des Moines Dental District Society, October 22, 1982. (Box 16)
    - Downingtown Schedule, October-December 1982. (Box 16)
    - American Academy of Gold Foil Dentists. Los Angeles, November 4, 1982. (Box 16)
    - American Diabetes Association. San Francisco, November 19, 1982. (Box 16)
    - Pasadena Medical Society, December 14, 1982. (Box 16)
  - 1983
    - East Coast District Dental Society. Miami Beach, January 21, 1983. (Box 16)
    - UCLA: Medical Students, January 27, 1983. (Box 16)
    - Radio Interview, January 30, 1983. (Box 16)
    - TV Show: "Consumer Line" - Trenton, New Jersey, February 10, 1983. (Box 16)
    - Academy of General Dentistry. Houston, February 24, 1983. (Box 16)
    - Northeast Dental Society, March 9, 1983. (Box 16)
    - PBS-TV: Detroit, March 9, 1983. (Box 16)
    - Yale: Medical Students. New Haven, March 10, 1983. (Box 16)
    - Columbia University Dental School, March 11, 1983. (Box 16)
    - Downingtown - New York, March 12-14, 1983. (Box 16)
    - Alpha Omega Dental. New York, April 8, 1983. (Box 16)
    - Ninth District Dental Society. West Point, April 13, 1983. (Box 16)
    - San Fernando Valley Optometric Society, April 27, 1983. (Box 16)
    - Santa Barbara Public Library, May 2, 1983. (Box 16)
    - Pennsylvania Dietetic Association, May 5, 1983. (Box 16)
    - TV: Washington, May 9, 1983. (Box 16)
    - St. Louis University Medical Center. Cardiac Rehabilitation, May 13, 1983. (Box 16)
    - Nutrition Symposium. Newport Beach, May 20-21, 1983. (Box 16)
    - Washington - Downingtown, June 2-5, 1983. (Box 16)
    - Pacific Coast Society of Orthodontists. Los Angeles, June 6, 1983. (Box 16)
    - American Society of Dentistry for Children. Los Angeles, June 7, 1983. (Box 16)
    - Oklahoma City Heart Conference, June 9-11, 1983. (Box 16)
    - Academy of General Dentistry. Toronto, July 16-20, 1983. (Box 16)
    - Aerobics Wellness Seminar. Dallas, August 15, 1983. (Box 16)
    - Dr. Ernest Wynder, September 13, 1983. (Box 16)
    - Frozen Foods Festival, September 13, 1983. (Box 16)
    - New York City Marathon, October 22, 1983. (Box 16)
    - PR Tour: Simon & Schuster, October 24-November 16, 1983. (Box 16)
    - 700 Club. Virginia Beach, November 21-22, 1983. (Box 16)
    - Washington University. St. Louis, November 30, 1983. (Box 16)
    - The Guardians. Los Angeles, December 13, 1983. (Box 16)
  - 1984
    - Radio-Telephone Interviews, January-February 1984. (Box 16)
    - "Mid-Morning L.A." - TV, February 9, 1984. (Box 16)
    - Book Tour: Simon & Schuster, February 20-March 2, 1984. (Box 16)
    - California Society of Dentistry for Children, March 2-4, 1984. (Box 16)
    - Cardiothoracic Symposium. San Diego, March 10, 1984. (Box 16)
    - TV Interview, March 19, 1984. (Box 16)
    - D.C. Dental Meeting, April 8, 1984. (Box 16)
    - Downingtown, April 5-9, 1984. (Box 16)
    - Pritikin Foods Promotion. Tucson, April 15-20, 1984. (Box 16)
    - Denver Triathlon: Thompson Kitchens, July 27-28,1984. (Box 16)
    - Life Underwriters. Vancouver, September 28, 1984. (Box 16)
    - Academy of Dentistry Intern. Atlanta, October 21, 1984. (Box 16)
    - Roane-Anderson County Medical Society. Tennessee, October 30, 1984. (Box 16)
- Nathan Pritikin Correspondence With Medical/Professionals:, 1976-1977
  - Approximately 27 files. (Box 17)
- Nathan Pritikin Correspondence With Medical/Professionals:, 1978-1979
  - Approximately 22 files. (Box 18)
- Nathan Pritikin Correspondence With Medical/Professionals, 1980-1985
  - Approximately 25 files. (Box 19)
- Contacts with other Researchers: Research Interest, Miscellaneous
  (See also Box no.8 for Diabetes Researchers)
  - Bryant, Dr. Vaughn (Anthropologist). (Box 19)
  - Blankenhorn, Dr. David (USC). (Box 19)
  - Brown, Dr. Michael. (Box 19)
  - Connor, Dr. William. (Box 19)
  - Castelli, Dr. William. (Box 19)
  - Dreyfus, Dr. Pierre. (Box 19)
  - Droubay, Dr. Peter. (Box 19)
  - Eliahou, Dr. H.E. (Box 19)
  - Falsetti, Dr. Herman. (Box 19)
  - Finney, Dr. James. (Box 19)
  - Fisher, Dr. Martin. (Box 19)
  - Grundy, Dr. Scott. (Box 19)
  - Jones, Dr. Robert. (Box 19)
  - Kempner, Dr. Walter. (Box 19)
  - Leaf, Dr. Alexander. (Box 19)
  - Levine, Dr. Rachmiel. (Box 19)
  - Lucas, Dr. Charles - Power, Dr. Laurence. (Box 19)
  - Mazess, Dr. Richard. (Box 19)
  - Maxwell, Dr. Edwin (D.D.S.). (Box 19)
  - Morrison, Dr. Lester M. (Box 19)
  - Palgi, Aviva, Ph.D. (Box 19)
  - Pauling, Dr. Linus. (Box 19)
  - Rapaport, Dr. Felix. (Box 19)
  - Raskin, Dr. Philip. (Box 19)
  - Swank, Dr. Roy. (Box 19)
  - Silberman, Dr. Richard. (Box 19)
  - Vignes, Dr. A.J. (Box 19)
  - Other researchers, miscellaneous. (Box 19)
  - Research Interest: Miscellaneous
    - Gerontology Researchers/Educators. (Box 19)
    - Cholestyramine/Plaque Regression. (Box 19)
    - Paris II Study (Persantine - Aspirin). (Box 19)
    - Research correspondence re weight-loss book. (Box 19)
    - Nathan Pritikin contact with lay persons (special regimen). (Box 19)
    - Foreign translations. (Box 19)
- Public Influence
  - Competitive Centers and Programs: I. Operated by Former Pritikin Associates or Employees
    - Bennett, Cleaves, M.D. (Box 20)
    - Delgado, Nick. (Box 20)
    - Leonard, Jon - Tucson Institute of Health. (Box 20)
    - Horning, Merritt, M.D. (Box 20)
    - Taylor, Glen. (Box 20)
    - Whitaker, Julian, M.D. (Box 20)
    - Wiegle, Bill. (Box 20)
    - Zifferblatt, Dr. Steven. (Box 20)
    - Other competitors previously associated with Pritikin. (Box 20)
  - Competitive Centers and Programs: II. Other Probably Influenced By Pritikin's Example
    - California Primary Physicians. (Box 20)
    - CHEER Program, Dr. Charles Kleeman. (Box 20)
    - Ben-Oni, Dr. Molka. (Box 20)
    - Fox, Dr. Arnold. (Box 20)
    - Haas, Dr. Robert. (Box 20)
    - Sircus, Dr. Sidney. (Box 20)
    - Weimar Institute. (Box 20)
    - West, Dr. Larry. (Box 20)
    - Competitors: Miscellaneous. (Box 20)
  - New Longevity Centers and Programs: Cooperators
    - Medical people wanting to start similar programs in U.S. (Box 20)
    - Pritikin and associates: East Coast Center. (Box 20)
    - Medical and lay people wanting to start similar programs. (Box 20)
    - Medical and lay people wanting to start similar programs (abroad). (Box 20)
    - Centers using Pritikin book and brochures. (Box 20)
    - Helix (England): Dodson-Keable. (Box 20)
    - Cardiofitness Center/Systems. (Box 20)
  - Followers or Supporters: Nutritional/Health Organizations
    - American Health Foundation: Dr. Ernest Wynder. (Box 20)
    - American Nutrition Society, Pasadena. (Box 20)
    - Center for Science, Public Interest: Dr. Michael Jacobson. (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous organizations. (Box 20)
  - Followers/Supporters: Institutions
    - Military Personnel - Supporters. (Box 20)
    - Prisons. (Box 20)
    - Nursing Homes; Senior housing. (Box 20)
    - Followers: Outreach programs for poor. (Box 20)
    - Fenton Foundation. (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous institutions. (Box 20)
  - M.D. Referrals by Longevity Center
    - Physicians referral of patients by Longevity Center. (Box 20)
  - Santa Barbara Area Medical Community
    - Ackerman, Dr. John. (Box 20)
    - Robinson, Dr. Miles. (Box 20)
    - "Friendly" physicians - Santa Barbara. (Box 20)
    - "Neutral" or hostile physicians - Santa Barbara. (Box 20)
    - Medical Society of Santa Barbara. (Box 20)
    - Burns, Wyman, D.D.S. (Box 20)
    - Direct Relief Foundation. (Box 20)
  - Followers/Supporters: Physicians: I, II, III
    - Belsky, Dr. Marvin. (Box 20)
    - Cooper, Dr. Kenneth (Cooper Clinic, Dallas). (Box 20)
    - Douglass, Dr. John. (Box 20)
    - Fogel, Dr. Richard. (Box 20)
    - Friedman, Dr. Meyer. (Box 20)
    - Litzow, Dr. Thaddeus. (Box 20)
    - Loop, Dr. Floyd. (Box 20)
    - McDougall, Dr. John. (Box 20)
    - Nalbandian, Dr. Robert. (Box 20)
    - Nequin, Dr. Noel. (Box 20)
    - Power, Dr. Lawrence. (Box 20)
    - Retherford, Dr. Ralph. (Box 20)
    - Rosin, Dr. Ben. (Box 20)
    - Silverstein, Dr. Robert. (Box 20)
    - Stuppy, Dr. Laurence. (Box 20)
    - Talbot, Dr. John. (Box 20)
    - Wukasch, Dr. Don. (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous followers/supporters, physician/dentist. (Box 20)
  - Followers or Supporters: Students and Educators
    - Pritkin Program on college campuses. (Box 20)
    - Junker, Dr. Louis - economist. (Box 20)
    - Insurance companies; Health education. (Box 20)
    - Students: Chiropractic. (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous health educators. (Box 20)
  - Dental Interest in Program
    - Sheets, Dr. Charilyn, D.D.S. (Box 20)
    - Dental interest. (Box 20)
  - Followers or Supporters: Suggestions
    - Diet Suggestions. (Box 20)
    - Expansion of program. (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous groups/individuals. (Box 20)
  - Followers or Supporters: Miscellaneous Prominent People
    - Brown, Governor Jerry. (Box 20)
    - Cousins, Norman. (Box 20)
    - Gordon, Jack (State Senator). (Box 20)
    - MacLaine, Shirley. (Box 20)
    - Scott, Willard. (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous prominent people. (Box 20)
  - Supporters: Media (Partial)
    - Diane Broughton. (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous. (Box 20)
  - Physician Interest in Program
    (See also: N.P. Correspondence with Medical Professionals)
    - Ulene, Dr. Art. (Box 20)
    - Government agency physicians. (Box 20)
    - Foreign. (Box 20)
  - Restaurants Catering to Pritikin Dieters
    - "Pritikin" on restaurant menus. (Box 20)
  - Food Products Developed for Others
    - Continental non-fat yogurt. (Box 20)
  - Food Products Endorsements/Acceptability/Interest
    - Food companies seeking business or endorsement. (Box 20)
    - Vita-Mix Corporation: William and Ruth Barnard. (Box 20)
    - Product acceptability. (Box 20)
    - Quaker Oats Company. (Box 20)
- Public Dialogue
  - Scientific Press: JAMA - N.P. Letter: (Letters Answered), March 2, 1984
    - [No further description available]. (Box 21)
  - Scientific Press: JAMA - Lundberg (JAMA editor)-Pritikin Correspondence, (1983)
    - Pritikin letter to JAMA editor; accepted for publication., (1983) (Box 21)
    - Correspondence of Pritikin and Lundberg (editor). (Box 21)
    - JAMA: Enclosures for letter to Lundberg ()., June 28, 1983 (Box 21)
    - Pritikin letter to JAMA editor: TV interview., (1983) (Box 21)
  - Scientific Press: JAMA - Pritikin Diet and Studies of Other Investigators
    - Canadian diet study (Dr. G. Brown & Pritikin diet, )., October 1981 (Box 21)
    - Ornish study: JAMA report, (January 1983). (Box 21)
  - Scientific Press: JAMA - Review of Pritikin programs by Therese Mondeika, (1980)
    - Mondeika review - JAMA (); Pritikin rebuttals., January 4, 1980 (Box 21)
    - Pritikin-JAMA correspondence re Mondeika review. (Box 21)
    - Public criticism of Mondeika review: Dr. James Rigg. (Box 21)
    - Public criticisms/interest in Mondeika review. (Box 21)
    - Media response. (Box 21)
    - Inquiry letters from JAMA readers in response to Pritikin's rebuttal to Mondeika review. (Box 21)
  - Scientific Press: JAMA - Article on Pritikin Diet, (1976 and Earlier)
    - JAMA: Paul Sampson article, (1975-76). (Box 21)
    - JAMA: LFC Study announcement, (1974). (Box 21)
  - Scientific Press: Miscellaneous Publications
    - American Council, Science & Health: News and Views. (Box 21)
    - American Journal of Cosmetic Surgery. (Box 21)
    - American Medical News. (Box 21)
    - Caduceus. (Box 21)
    - Lancet: Humorous editorial, (September 28, 1985). (Box 21)
    - Mental Acuity, Merzbacher study. (Box 21)
    - Medical Month. (Box 21)
    - Medical Tribune. (Box 21)
    - Medical University Newsletters. (Box 21)
    - Medical World News. (Box 21)
    - Preventive Medicine. (Box 21)
    - Scandinavian Journal of Gastroenterology (Dr. Hugh Trowell). (Box 21)
    - UCLA Health Insights. (Box 21)
    - Miscellaneous scientific press. (Box 21)
  - Book Criticisms
    - Criticisms, correspondence. (Box 21)
    - Reviews of books. (Box 21)
  - Consumer Reports Article
    - Consumer Reports article - Pritikin rebuttal. (Box 21)
    - Media response and interest. (Box 21)
    - Pritikin - Consumer Reports correspondence. (Box 21)
    - Letters to Consumer Reports in support of Pritikin diet. (Box 21)
    - Readers' requests for Pritikin answer to Consumer Reports criticisms. (Box 21)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence re Consumer Reports article. (Box 21)
  - Diet Ratings, Food Writers Reviews
    - Diet ratings. (Box 21)
    - Theodore Berland: Diet ratings. (Box 21)
    - Nutritional controversy: Jane Brody. (Box 21)
    - Controversy with Kayser's health stores. (Box 21)
    - Nutrition controversy: Food writers. (Box 21)
  - Popular Diets
    - Cambridge diet. (Box 21)
    - Weight Watchers. (Box 21)
  - Popular diets: Atkins Diet
    - Pritikin-Atkins "Debate" (pre-litigation). (Box 21)
    - Others' critiques of Atkins (or Atkins-type) diet. (Box 21)
    - Atkins vs. Pritikin lawsuit: Legal documents. (Box 21)
    - Media reports on Atkins vs. Pritikin lawsuit. (Box 21)
  - Miscellaneous Nutritional Controversies
    - [No further description available]. (Box 21)
    - Dale Alexander. (Box 21)
    - Winick, Dr. Myron. (Box 21)
    - Alfin-Slater, Dr. Roslyn. (Box 21)
  - Authorities
    - Gotto, Dr. Antonio - AHA dietary guidelines. (Box 21)
    - Herbert, Dr. Victor. (Box 21)
    - Mayer, Dr. Jean. (Box 21)
    - Olson, Dr. Robert. (Box 21)
    - Oster, Dr. Kurt. (Box 21)
    - Solomon, Dr. Neil. (Box 21)
  - Institutions
    - A.D.A. - Los Angeles, Janet Segal, R.D. (Box 21)
    - American Dietetic Association. (Box 21)
    - American Heart Association. (Box 21)
    - American Medical Association. (Box 21)
    - Arizona Heart Institute. (Box 21)
    - California Medical Association. (Box 21)
    - Los Angeles County Medical Association. (Box 21)
    - Humana Hospital (Schroeder). (Box 21)
    - Meat Institute. (Box 21)
    - National Confectioners Association. (Box 21)
    - UCLA. (Box 21)
    - Harvard Medical School Study. (Box 21)
    - Cedars-Sinai Medical Center. (Box 21)
    - Miscellaneous: Institutions. (Box 21)
  - Notable Patients at Centers
    - [No further description available]. (Box 21)
  - Followers (Prominent) in Corporate World
    - Coors, William K. (Box 21)
    - Equitable Life Insurance Company. (Box 21)
    - Pritikin Superfit insurance program. (Box 21)
    - Corporate programs favorably influenced. (Box 21)
    - Thomas Field. (Box 21)
    - Miles Rubin. (Box 21)
    - Martin Stone. (Box 21)
    - Dr. Cory Servass (Saturday Evening Post). (Box 21)
    - Corporate influence: Miscellaneous. (Box 21)
- Testimonials
  - Athletes. (Box 22)
  - Physicians. (Box 22)
    (See also: Correspondence with medical/professionals, Boxes 13-15)
  - Dentists. (Box 22)
  - Pilots. (Box 22)
  - Professionals. (Box 22)
  - Teenagers. (Box 22)
  - Foreign. (Box 22)
  - Thomas Field. (Box 22)
  - Nathan Muchnick. (Box 22)
  - Eula Weaver. (Box 22)
  - Testimonials: Patients
    - Interviews of Santa Monica Center participants. (Box 22)
    - 1977-1987., (9 Files) (Box 22)
  - Testimonials - Non-Participants:, 1975-1987; (10 Files)
    - [No further description available]. (Box 22)
  - Testimonial Letters: Pritikin Guide to Restaurant Dining
    - [No further description available]. (Box 22)
  - Longevity Centers: II
    - Longevity Center Administration - Santa Barbara Beginnings
      - Concept origin. (Box 26)
        (See also: Long Beach Study, Box no.5)
      - Early staff meetings. (Box 26)
      - Organization. (Box 26)
      - Promotional activities: Pilot Association, airlines, etc. (Box 26)
      - Original research/therapy goals for Center. (Box 26)
      - Longevity Center: History of name. (Box 26)
      - Program evaluation of patients. (Box 26)
      - Application forms/Information, etc. (Box 26)
      - Telephone Inquiry forms; screening Pritikin's calls. (Box 26)
      - Medical and medicolegal forms. (Box 26)
    - Longevity Center Administration; Santa Monica
      - Transition to Santa Monica. (Box 26)
      - Personnel. (Box 26)
    - Early Longevity Center Locations (Santa Barbara, Ventura)
      - Holiday Inn - Ventura. (Box 26)
      - Howard Johnson Lodge. (Box 26)
      - Mar Monte Hotel. (Box 26)
      - Finding a suitable location - Santa Barbara. (Box 26)
    - Longevity Center Medical Program: Admission Guidelines
      - [No further description available]. (Box 26)
    - Longevity Center beginnings: Legal Matters
      - Santa Barbara County Health Department. (Box 26)
      - California Board of Quality Assurance. (Box 26)
      - LRI: Legal, miscellaneous. (Box 26)
    - Longevity Center Medical Program: Beginnings
      - Patient group sessions with physicians/lab schedules. (Box 26)
      - Laboratory testing. (Box 26)
      - Physician's handbook for Center physicians. (Box 26)
      - Protocol. (Box 26)
      - Patients: Follow-up and patients' suggestions. (Box 26)
      - Hyperbaric chamber; claudication patients, use on. (Box 26)
      - Administration: Forms used and memos. (Box 26)
      - Medical Office stationery (evolving). (Box 26)
    - Longevity Center Medical Program: More Recent Material
      - Reading material for new doctor at Center. (Box 26)
      - Laboratory testing. (Box 26)
      - Patient instructions. (Box 26)
      - Patient education. (Box 26)
      - Relations with medical staff. (Box 26)
    - Longevity Center: Medical Controversies
      - Miscellaneous medical controversies. (Box 26)
    - Longevity Center Physiological and Stress Management Programs
      - Staffing. (Box 26)
      - Programs. (Box 26)
      - Nathan's views re stress. (Box 26)
      - Applicants. (Box 26)
    - Longevity Center Exercise Program
      - Exercise program: Beginnings. (Box 26)
      - Exercise program:, 1981. (Box 26)
      - Exercise program: Miscellaneous. (Box 26)
    - Longevity Center Dietary Plan: Cookbooks
      - Longevity Center cookbook for participants, (1981). (Box 26)
      - Longevity Center (early) participants cookbooks. (Box 26)
      - Longevity Center (early) institutional cookbook. (Box 26)
    - Longevity Center Dietary Plan: Antecedents
      - : Recipes developed., 1974-75 (Box 26)
      - : Recipes for a diabetic., 1974 (Box 26)
    - Longevity Center Dietary Plan: Miscellaneous
      - Modifying the Longevity Center diet for weight loss and other needs. (Box 26)
      - Rationale. (Box 26)
      - Early menu planning. (Box 26)
      - Beverages. (Box 26)
      - Ongoing nutritional research related to diet served. (Box 26)
    - Longevity Center Lectures: I and II
      - Early guideline information given patients. (Box 26)
      - Orientation lectures and material. (Box 26)
      - Lecture schedule. (Box 26)
      - Group counseling sessions led by Nathan. (Box 26)
      - Lecture hand-outs. (Box 26)
      - Lecture hand-outs:, 1977. (Box 26)
      - Patient medical education material. (Box 26)
    - Longevity Center "Graduation" Ceremonies - Diplomas
      (See also: Box no.20, "Creative Tributes")
    - Longevity Center Smoke-Ending Program
      - Smoke-ending program. (Box 26)
      - Jack Crane. (Box 26)
    - Longevity Center: Log of Eighth Session:, November 1976.
      - [No further description available]. (Box 26)
    - Longevity Center. Santa Monica: Program Schedules (Daily, Weekly) - Samples
      - [No further description available]. (Box 26)
    - Longevity Center Promotional Material: Reply Forms and Enclosures
      - Early form letters for inquiries. (Box 26)
      - Mailing enclosures: Case histories and description of regimen. (Box 26)
    - Longevity Center promotional material: Ads, brochures, fact sheets
      - Ad criticism. (Box 26)
      - Ads: Longevity Center and PM program. (Box 26)
      - Longevity Center brochures. (Box 26)
      - Fact sheets. (Box 26)
    - Longevity Center promotional material: Sent to physicians
      - Promotional mailings - Santa Barbara. (Box 26)
      - Promotional mailings - Santa Monica. (Box 26)
      - Excerpt: "For the Health Professional" (From: Pritikin Program for Diet and Exercise"). (Box 26)
      - Longevity Center exhibit - California Medical Association -, February 1980. (Box 26)
    - Pritikin Longevity Center: Alumni program
      - Alumni organization meetings/leadership. (Box 26)
      - Alumni sessions at Longevity Center. (Box 26)
      - Newsletters. (Box 26)
      - Follow-up medical testing. (Box 26)
      - Nathan Pritikin letter to alumni. (Box 26)
      - Advice to alumni about post-Center schedule. (Box 26)
- Testimonials: (65th) Birthday Book; Creative Tributes; Posthumous Tributes-Articles
  - "Health Goals" Project - Testimonials. (Box 23)
  - Birthday Book concept. (Box 23)
  - Birthday Book: Testimonials - Replies: I-VI, (6 files) (Box 23)
  - Creative Tributes. (Box 23)
  - Posthumous Tributes
    - Memorial Resolution: California State Assembly, (May 1, 1985). (Box 23)
    - Nathan Pritikin memorial contributions. (Box 23)
    - Medical community. (Box 23)
    - McGovern, Senator George - eulogizer. (Box 23)
    - Long Beach study patients. (Box 23)
    - People he helped. (Box 23)
    - General public. (Box 23)
    - Old friends. (Box 23)
    - Co-workers, staff. (Box 23)
    - Prominent people (miscellaneous). (Box 23)
  - Media: Posthumous
    - Newspaper reports - Autopsy reports. (Box 23)